sarahtitus.com 2019-05-03

# Full Disclosure & Privacy Policy - Sarah Titus

_Last updated: May 24, 2018._

Per the FTC regulations, this is a full explanation of how and when I am compensated on SarahTitus.com.

SarahTitus.com began as a way to reach out to many women who want the opportunity to be able to stay home with their little ones, but don’t know how to go about doing it. It was inspired by a majority of my friends and acquaintances wanting me to teach them these money saving tricks and skills, as well as how to make money from home to supplement their income once they quit their 9-5 jobs. As a lack of time grew in being able to teach each one of them on a personal level and in order to have the opportunity to reach millions of others at the same time, led by God, the site was born. Over time, as I got more involved and more and more readers were enjoying my content and spending quite a bit of time on the site in a desire to learn more, I became a full-time, professional blogger.

In order to keep all of my blog content free of charge, but still be able to pay all the costs associated with running an online business (hosting fees, domain name, blog design, my own time and that of those who help me), there are many ways in which I am compensated.

SarahTitus.com is a labor of love. Many people tell me I was born to blog, and I truly enjoy every minute of it and the impact it makes on others lives. I just also happen to receive funds for doing my ‘job’ and spreading that message.

## My opinions and morals

The integrity of SarahTitus.com is of the utmost importance to me. I will never promote anything that I fully do not believe in, even if offered to be compensated for it, and have turned down many offers as such in my time blogging. Likewise, I will not promote something that is not valuable to you, as my reader, even if I DO personally believe in it, nor would I promote anything that does not fit into the specified categories on this site.

If I say I like something, I do. If I say I hate something, I do. Most of the companies that I promote are companies that I have used long before I ever started a blog.

This blog is an outstretch of the hand of God, and what He has done in my life. If something doesn’t line up with that core mission, it will not even be considered. My witness as a Christian is the most important thing to me, and I will not sacrifice that for any amount of cash or personal relationships. Those that know me best, have seen this practice played out in my life.

## Underwritten Posts / Product Reviews

On occasion, I will accept a product review if it lines up with the sites’ overall theme, and I think you, as a reader, could benefit from the information. Never can my opinion be bought, and the product review is 100% my words, my opinions, and my thoughts with 100% honesty. If a product or service is mentioned, and you do not see the disclaimer on the page, I was not compensated for it. It just happened that I thought you might appreciate the information.

## Guest Posts

On occasion, I will accept guest posts to be written by others and published on this site, if they line up with the overall theme, and I think you would benefit from the information. Be assured that I only do this with individuals that I believe in, and would be of genuine interest to you.

## Affiliate Marketing

Another way in which I am compensated is through sales or leads generated through affiliate marketing links.

Again, it is important for me to mention that I will never put a link up just to make money. I am extremely picky over what I chose to promote, and everything is prayed over before making my decision. Most of the companies I have affiliate marketing accounts with, are ones that I have had before I began blogging, and have personally used myself throughout the years.

Some of my personal favorite companies that I use and promote are:

  * [Amazon](https://www.sarahtitus.com/amazon.com) (I am a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associate Program)

Clicking on an affiliate link and making a purchase or signing up for a service will be earning me a commission and helping me to keep this blog free.

## Banner Ads

In my making money section, I accept whole-page banner ads for direct selling and network marketing companies. These companies must be approved by me and must be 100% legitimate companies. There are too many scams out there for work at home situations, and I do not take this section of the site lightly. These companies will only be ones that have a proven track record of being scam-free and safe to work for. The leaders who are promoted for each company also have been approved and there will only be one representative per company. I will not advertise two reps simultaneously. During the time frame that a representative has a whole-page banner ad placed on this site, other reps from the same company cannot be considered. This is done to avoid confusion for my readers. It is also done because I’m an extremely loyal type of person and would not want someone to do that to me.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Where necessary, SarahTitus.com uses cookies to store information about a visitor’s preferences and history in order to better serve the visitor and/or present the visitor with customized content. Advertising partners and other third-parties may also use cookies, scripts, and/or web beacons to track visitors to our site in order to display advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the third parties through their own servers and is subject to their own privacy policies.

To make this site work properly, we sometimes place small data files called cookies on your device. Most all big websites do this.

**What are cookies?**

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, font size and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another.

**How do we use cookies?**

SarahTitus.com uses cookies to let you perform authenticated actions like signing into your personal account. Additionally cookies may be used for advertising purposes.

**How to control cookies**

You can control and/or delete cookies as you wish – for details, see [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit a site and some services and functionalities may not work.

## Controlling Your Privacy

You can change your browser settings to disable cookies if you have any privacy concerns. Disabling cookies for all sites is not recommended as it may interfere with your use of some sites. The best option is to disable or enable cookies on a site-by-site basis. Run a Google search for instructions on how to block cookies and other tracking mechanisms.

## Google Advertising

Any ads served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. Learn how to [opt out of Google’s cookie usage](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/). As mentioned above, any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

## Medical/Health Disclaimer

By law, I am required to say: This information is not intended to cure, diagnose or treat medical conditions, nor is it a substitute for the product user’s guide.  Please consult with a physician before beginning this or any other new health care program.  Any information with regard to personal testimonies about Richway International’s or DoTerra Essential Oil products do not reflect or represent Richway International’s or DoTerra’s product claims.  These statements have not been evaluated by the FDA.

## Trust and Committment

Maintaining your trust with me is vital on this blog and in my own personal life with everyone I meet. I will not do anything to purposely misalign that trust, nor will I ever share anything that I personally do not use or believe in wholeheartedly.

## Privacy Policy

I use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit my site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click here for the [opt out page.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

## WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?

**Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** : We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

**Automatically-Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

## HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED

**We may use the information collected in the following ways:**

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To send you products you have purchased;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website;
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

## THIRD-PARTY **USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

**Personal data is collected by Website for the following purposes and using the following third-party service providers:**

**_Analytics_**

Analytics collected directly and Google Analytics

Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

Commercial affiliation

Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

_**Contacting the User**_

Contact form / Google docs spreadsheet

Personal Data: email address, first name, city/state

_**Ecommerce**_

Shopify (and including apps such as ConvertKit, Coupon Hero, Digital Downloads, Fraud Filter, Lucky Orange, Product Reviews, Product Reviews Addon, SendOwl)

Personal Data: email address, first and last name, item purchased, date purchased, total payment amount

_**Interaction with external social networks and platforms**_

Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets

Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

_**Managing contacts and sending messages**_

ConvertKit

Leadpages/Leadboxes

Personal Data: email address and first name (optional)

_**SPAM protection**_

Akismet

Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

_**Traffic optimization and distribution**_

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent.

### ANONYMOUS DATA

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

## PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION

If you leave a comment on this Website, your name and comment (and URL if entered) will be publicly visible.

## ADVERTISING

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Display Ads**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

**Retargeting Ads**

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, Pinterest, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

## NEWSLETTERS

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

## LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at the contact page at the bottom of this form to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to the contact page at the bottom of this form.

Amend – You may contact us at the contact page at the bottom of this form to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to the contact page at the bottom of this form.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law such as in the case of product sales.

### SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

### CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at the contact page at the bottom of this form and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

If you have any concerns about this policy, please feel free to [contact me](https://www.sarahtitus.com/contact/).
